<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nimke.nl - Intentionally Bilingual &amp; More on Nimke.nl</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Nimke.nl - Intentionally Bilingual &amp; More on Nimke.nl</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why we raise our child in non-native English</title><link>/bilingualism/read-more/why/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/read-more/why/</guid><description>My husband and I are both born and raised in the Netherlands, and our native language is Dutch. Why then, did we decide to raise our child in English, you might ask. Isn’t it enough to focus on just one language, especially since none of us has English as their mother tongue?
The simple answer to that question, is no. For us, just raising our daughter in Dutch is not enough and although it will be a challenge, we are determined to make the English work for us as a family.</description></item><item><title>Bilingualism: the Benefits</title><link>/bilingualism/read-more/benefits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/read-more/benefits/</guid><description>As bilingualism is often a necessity within multilingual families, added benefits are not really needed to convince people to raise their children in two or more languages. For families like my own however (native speakers of the majority language), learning about those benefits did tip the scales in favour of bilingualism. So what different benefits are there to bilingualism? In this post I will tell you the most important ones, divided in several categories.</description></item><item><title>When are you bilingual?</title><link>/bilingualism/start-here/areyoubilingual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/start-here/areyoubilingual/</guid><description>If you google bilingualism -or multilingualism-, you will find that there are more people who speak multiple languages, than people who only speak one language. Especially in Africa it seems that speaking two, or even three or four languages is quite common. In Europe, a lot of people can also speak English. If I ask around though, not a lot of people consider themselves bilingual. So what is it that makes a person, a bilingual person?</description></item><item><title>The types of bilingualism, explained</title><link>/bilingualism/start-here/typesbilingualism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/start-here/typesbilingualism/</guid><description>All roads lead to Rome, but it doesn’t mean all roads are similar. This is also true for bilingualism, as there are multiple paths a bilingual person can have taken. In this blog I will tell you the two main roads to follow. There is some overlap and extra paths, which I will also discuss.
The view on bilingualism that I will portray here, is based on timing. It’s pretty straightforward and doesn’t leave much to debate, apart from when exactly one part stops and the other starts.</description></item><item><title>When NOT to raise your child bilingual</title><link>/bilingualism/read-more/whennot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/read-more/whennot/</guid><description>As a bilingual mom and language lover, I’m quite the advocate for bilingualism. In my work as a speech therapist and most research I read, I see a lot of benefits of bilingualism. The advice to raise your child monolingual instead of multilingual seems for the most part, a thing of the past.
But are there circumstances in which raising your child bilingual is indeed not the way to go? In this blog I will try to tell you about precisely those circumstances, what kind of risks they form and the options you have.</description></item><item><title>Receptive bilingualism: when you don’t speak the language</title><link>/bilingualism/read-more/receptive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/read-more/receptive/</guid><description>In the first post of &amp;ldquo;start here&amp;rdquo;, I have explained what it means to be bilingual. Although the definition is not set in stone, the basic idea is that a person speaks two or more languages in his daily life. I already talked about a specific situation, in which you do understand the language, but cannot speak it.
As communication is key, this still can be a form of bilingualism. The term for this is a receptive bilingual, also known as a non-speaking bilingual or passive bilingual.</description></item><item><title>The strategies</title><link>/bilingualism/start-here/strategies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/start-here/strategies/</guid><description>In short, there are 5 main strategies or ways on how to raise your child bilingual (or even trilingual). Choosing the strategy that suits your particular family, wishes and abilities is very important for parents. I repeat, for the parents. Many parents need a structure in which to work, in order not to neglect one of the languages in the long run. For the children, it doesn’t matter whatever you do.</description></item><item><title>Family Language Policy</title><link>/bilingualism/start-here/familylanguagepolicy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/start-here/familylanguagepolicy/</guid><description>A Family Language Policy is a detailed plan describing the languages and language strategies used in a family. This plan often includes the ideology towards (bilingual) parenting and the goals that a family has set considering their bilingualism.
Before I tell you more, there are two important things to discuss.
First of all, you can start making your family language policy at any time or period of your child’s life. Ideally you start planning before he/she is born, or soon after.</description></item><item><title>The cultural status of a language</title><link>/bilingualism/read-more/culturalstatus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/read-more/culturalstatus/</guid><description>When speaking of bilingualism or multilingualism, many forms and ways are possible. Many aspects can affect a child&amp;rsquo;s bilingualism, not just how many languages ​​are spoken or in what way the children are introduced. The “choice” of the language itself, and the cultural status of the particular languages in society, can sometimes make a big difference in the chances of a successful bilingual language development. In this blog, I will tell you more about the differences and risks of these cultural aspects of languages, and explain some of the definitions that are used to explain it.</description></item><item><title>Defining terminology</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/terminology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/terminology/</guid><description>In this series I will talk about the language development or acquisition of a child, both monolingual and bilingual (or multilingual). Before I dive into the subject in my posts, here is a introductory post about the different stages and other terminology I use. Other posts can use similar or different terminology, but overall I know that the information itself is consistent.
Age notation Please note that ages are indicated in years;months.</description></item><item><title>Signing AND Speaking?</title><link>/bilingualism/read-more/signingspeaking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/read-more/signingspeaking/</guid><description>On this page I will talk about how I use sign language when communicating with the children in my work. There are different ways to incorporate signs in communication, and this is not only used for Deaf* children (or adults). A frequently heard term is baby sign language, and another term is sign supported speech. I will first explain what these terms mean, what they have in common and what the differences are.</description></item><item><title>Trilingual or more</title><link>/bilingualism/start-here/trilingual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/start-here/trilingual/</guid><description>On this page I will talk specifically about trilingual families, and families with even more than 3 languages. In general, not much is different with raising a trilingual child, then a bilingual child. All of my advise and information I give about raising children with 2 languages, also work and are intended for children with 3, 4 and 5 languages and so on. While officially the term bilingual means two languages, whenever I use the term bilingual in my posts, I actually mean 2 languages or more.</description></item><item><title>Preverbal stage (0-1 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/preverbal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/preverbal/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about the preverbal stage, that usually last from (before) birth until the 1-year mark. As the name suggests, this is the period of language development “before speech”. As for this stage there are almost no differences between monolingual and simultaneous bilingual development, I will discuss these two together.
Broadly speaking, babies develop their receptive language (understanding) first and their productive language (speaking or signing) later.</description></item><item><title>The one-word stage (1;0-1;6 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/oneword/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/oneword/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about part 1 of the early linguistic stage. The early linguistic stage usually lasts from the 1-year mark until the age of 2;6 years. This first part is called the one-word stage or the holophrastic phase (just a fancy term for &amp;lsquo;one word&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;). As the name is quite clear, this is the period of language development that a child speaks in singular words, and not yet in sentences.</description></item><item><title>The two-word and telegraphic stage (1;6-2;6 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/telegraphic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/telegraphic/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about part 2 of the early linguistic stage. The early linguistic stage usually lasts from the 1-year mark until the age of 2;6 years. Once the one-word stage is finished, the two-word stage begins (sounds logical doesn’t it?). This is sometimes seen as part of the telegraphic stage (which I explain below). In this stage children start combining their words into small sentences, making their communication much more understandable.</description></item><item><title>Stage of linguistic differentiation (2;6-5 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/differentiation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/differentiation/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about the stage of linguistic differentiation. This stage starts around the age of 2;6 years and lasts until the age of 5 years. In this stage the children’s social and cognitive skills improve massively, alongside the so called language explosion they seem to acquire. Everything goes fast and is learned fast, before you know it the child is 4 or 5 years old and no longer talking in that telegraphic style, but speaks in well versed sentences which are even fully intelligible!</description></item><item><title>Stage of linguistic completion (5+ years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/completion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/completion/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about the last stage of language development and acquisition. Logically it is called the stage of linguistic completion, in which the language development is completed. Technically, everybody always continues to develop and there is never a moment in time that language is absolutely completed. In the practical sense though, it means that components like grammar and articulation are without any developmental faults around the age of 10 years.</description></item></channel></rss>