<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Language development on Nimke.nl</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/</link><description>Recent content in Language development on Nimke.nl</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/bilingualism/language-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Defining terminology</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/terminology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/terminology/</guid><description>In this series I will talk about the language development or acquisition of a child, both monolingual and bilingual (or multilingual). Before I dive into the subject in my posts, here is a introductory post about the different stages and other terminology I use. Other posts can use similar or different terminology, but overall I know that the information itself is consistent.
Age notation Please note that ages are indicated in years;months.</description></item><item><title>Preverbal stage (0-1 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/preverbal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/preverbal/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about the preverbal stage, that usually last from (before) birth until the 1-year mark. As the name suggests, this is the period of language development “before speech”. As for this stage there are almost no differences between monolingual and simultaneous bilingual development, I will discuss these two together.
Broadly speaking, babies develop their receptive language (understanding) first and their productive language (speaking or signing) later.</description></item><item><title>The one-word stage (1;0-1;6 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/oneword/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/oneword/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about part 1 of the early linguistic stage. The early linguistic stage usually lasts from the 1-year mark until the age of 2;6 years. This first part is called the one-word stage or the holophrastic phase (just a fancy term for &amp;lsquo;one word&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;). As the name is quite clear, this is the period of language development that a child speaks in singular words, and not yet in sentences.</description></item><item><title>The two-word and telegraphic stage (1;6-2;6 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/telegraphic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/telegraphic/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about part 2 of the early linguistic stage. The early linguistic stage usually lasts from the 1-year mark until the age of 2;6 years. Once the one-word stage is finished, the two-word stage begins (sounds logical doesn’t it?). This is sometimes seen as part of the telegraphic stage (which I explain below). In this stage children start combining their words into small sentences, making their communication much more understandable.</description></item><item><title>Stage of linguistic differentiation (2;6-5 years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/differentiation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/differentiation/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about the stage of linguistic differentiation. This stage starts around the age of 2;6 years and lasts until the age of 5 years. In this stage the children’s social and cognitive skills improve massively, alongside the so called language explosion they seem to acquire. Everything goes fast and is learned fast, before you know it the child is 4 or 5 years old and no longer talking in that telegraphic style, but speaks in well versed sentences which are even fully intelligible!</description></item><item><title>Stage of linguistic completion (5+ years)</title><link>/bilingualism/language-development/completion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bilingualism/language-development/completion/</guid><description>In this post I will talk about the last stage of language development and acquisition. Logically it is called the stage of linguistic completion, in which the language development is completed. Technically, everybody always continues to develop and there is never a moment in time that language is absolutely completed. In the practical sense though, it means that components like grammar and articulation are without any developmental faults around the age of 10 years.</description></item></channel></rss>