<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Read more on Nimke.nl</title><link>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/</link><description>Recent content in Read more on Nimke.nl</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why we raise our child in non-native English</title><link>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/why/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/why/</guid><description>My husband and I are both born and raised in the Netherlands, and our native language is Dutch. Why then, did we decide to raise our child in English, you might ask. Isn’t it enough to focus on just one language, especially since none of us has English as their mother tongue?
The simple answer to that question, is no. For us, just raising our daughter in Dutch is not enough and although it will be a challenge, we are determined to make the English work for us as a family.</description></item><item><title>Bilingualism: the Benefits</title><link>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/benefits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/benefits/</guid><description>As bilingualism is often a necessity within multilingual families, added benefits are not really needed to convince people to raise their children in two or more languages. For families like my own however (native speakers of the majority language), learning about those benefits did tip the scales in favour of bilingualism. So what different benefits are there to bilingualism? In this post I will tell you the most important ones, divided in several categories.</description></item><item><title>When NOT to raise your child bilingual</title><link>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/whennot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/whennot/</guid><description>As a bilingual mom and language lover, I’m quite the advocate for bilingualism. In my work as a speech therapist and most research I read, I see a lot of benefits of bilingualism. The advice to raise your child monolingual instead of multilingual seems for the most part, a thing of the past.
But are there circumstances in which raising your child bilingual is indeed not the way to go? In this blog I will try to tell you about precisely those circumstances, what kind of risks they form and the options you have.</description></item><item><title>Receptive bilingualism: when you don’t speak the language</title><link>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/receptive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/receptive/</guid><description>In the first post of &amp;ldquo;start here&amp;rdquo;, I have explained what it means to be bilingual. Although the definition is not set in stone, the basic idea is that a person speaks two or more languages in his daily life. I already talked about a specific situation, in which you do understand the language, but cannot speak it.
As communication is key, this still can be a form of bilingualism. The term for this is a receptive bilingual, also known as a non-speaking bilingual or passive bilingual.</description></item><item><title>The cultural status of a language</title><link>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/culturalstatus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/culturalstatus/</guid><description>When speaking of bilingualism or multilingualism, many forms and ways are possible. Many aspects can affect a child&amp;rsquo;s bilingualism, not just how many languages ​​are spoken or in what way the children are introduced. The “choice” of the language itself, and the cultural status of the particular languages in society, can sometimes make a big difference in the chances of a successful bilingual language development. In this blog, I will tell you more about the differences and risks of these cultural aspects of languages, and explain some of the definitions that are used to explain it.</description></item><item><title>Signing AND Speaking?</title><link>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/signingspeaking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>nimke.nl/bilingualism/read-more/signingspeaking/</guid><description>On this page I will talk about how I use sign language when communicating with the children in my work. There are different ways to incorporate signs in communication, and this is not only used for Deaf* children (or adults). A frequently heard term is baby sign language, and another term is sign supported speech. I will first explain what these terms mean, what they have in common and what the differences are.</description></item></channel></rss>