<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Start here on Nimke.nl</title><link>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/</link><description>Recent content in Start here on Nimke.nl</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When are you bilingual?</title><link>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/areyoubilingual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/areyoubilingual/</guid><description>If you google bilingualism -or multilingualism-, you will find that there are more people who speak multiple languages, than people who only speak one language. Especially in Africa it seems that speaking two, or even three or four languages is quite common. In Europe, a lot of people can also speak English. If I ask around though, not a lot of people consider themselves bilingual. So what is it that makes a person, a bilingual person?</description></item><item><title>The types of bilingualism, explained</title><link>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/typesbilingualism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/typesbilingualism/</guid><description>All roads lead to Rome, but it doesn’t mean all roads are similar. This is also true for bilingualism, as there are multiple paths a bilingual person can have taken. In this blog I will tell you the two main roads to follow. There is some overlap and extra paths, which I will also discuss.
The view on bilingualism that I will portray here, is based on timing. It’s pretty straightforward and doesn’t leave much to debate, apart from when exactly one part stops and the other starts.</description></item><item><title>The strategies</title><link>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/strategies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/strategies/</guid><description>In short, there are 5 main strategies or ways on how to raise your child bilingual (or even trilingual). Choosing the strategy that suits your particular family, wishes and abilities is very important for parents. I repeat, for the parents. Many parents need a structure in which to work, in order not to neglect one of the languages in the long run. For the children, it doesn’t matter whatever you do.</description></item><item><title>Family Language Policy</title><link>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/familylanguagepolicy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/familylanguagepolicy/</guid><description>A Family Language Policy is a detailed plan describing the languages and language strategies used in a family. This plan often includes the ideology towards (bilingual) parenting and the goals that a family has set considering their bilingualism.
Before I tell you more, there are two important things to discuss.
First of all, you can start making your family language policy at any time or period of your child’s life. Ideally you start planning before he/she is born, or soon after.</description></item><item><title>Trilingual or more</title><link>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/trilingual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nimke.nl/bilingualism/start-here/trilingual/</guid><description>On this page I will talk specifically about trilingual families, and families with even more than 3 languages. In general, not much is different with raising a trilingual child, then a bilingual child. All of my advise and information I give about raising children with 2 languages, also work and are intended for children with 3, 4 and 5 languages and so on. While officially the term bilingual means two languages, whenever I use the term bilingual in my posts, I actually mean 2 languages or more.</description></item></channel></rss>